https://www.methodist.edu/about-mu/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Forward Together: Coronavirus Resource Web Site
Quick LinksmyMU PortalBlackboardCanvasGroupWise EmailGive to MUOnline ProgramsCampus DirectoryVirtual Campus TourBookstoreDavis Memorial LibraryPositions AvailableRequest a TranscriptRecent NewsUpcoming EventsPrivacy Policy MenuMENUMENUAcademicsGeneral InformationAccreditationAcademic CalendarAcademic CatalogueCourse & Exam SchedulesGraduationQuality Enhancement Plan (QEP)Request a TranscriptAcademic ProgramsAll Academic ProgramsGeneral EducationMU at Night & Extended LearningFort Bragg CampusMethodist University OnlineStudy AbroadEnrichment ProgramsAcademic AffairsAcademic ServicesDavis Memorial LibraryOffice of the RegistrarInternships & Experiential LearningCulture of ReadingTeaching & Learning CenterWriting CenterAbout MUWho We AreUniversity ProfileOur Vision & MissionMU & The UMCPresident & TrusteesAdministrative CabinetCampus DirectoryFor Campus VisitorsCampus MapsArea HotelsDriving DirectionsArts & Lecture SeriesMcCune GalleryEventsCampus OfficesAll Campus OfficesBookstoreBook Our VenuesHuman ResourcesOffice of Student AccountsUniversity RelationsAdmissionsDiscover MURequest More InformationVisit CampusCampus MapsApply NowAdmissions FAQAdmissions TypeFreshmenTransfer StudentsEvening StudentsOnline StudentsInternational StudentsGraduate StudentsAdmissions ResourcesAdmissions StaffAccepted StudentsNew Student OrientationSpecial Student StatusFinancial AidHow to ApplyApplying for AidFinancial Aid FAQNC Residency DeterminationFinancial Aid AppealsNet Price CalculatorTypes of AidAcademic/Merit ScholarshipsInstitutional ScholarshipsInternational Student AidStudent LoansVeteran ServicesMore InformationTuition & FeesFinancial Aid Terms & ConceptsFinancial Aid Key DatesSatisfactory Academic Progress (SAP)Financial Aid FormsStudent AffairsOffice of Student AffairsAbout Student AffairsCo-Curricular TranscriptStudent HandbookStudent FacilitiesNew Student OrientationSexual Violence Prevention & ResponseGetting InvolvedStudent Involvement CenterFraternity & Sorority LifeInternational ProgramsMulticultural AffairsCampus Recreation & IntramuralsClubs & OrganizationsStudent ResourcesCareer ServicesCommuting StudentsCounseling ServicesDining Services by AramarkHealth ServicesHousing & Residence LifePolice & Public SafetyAthleticsMen's TeamsBaseballBasketballCheerCross CountryFootballGolfLacrosseSoccerTennisTrack & FieldWomen's TeamsBasketballCheerCross CountryGolfLacrosseSoccerSoftballTennisTrack & FieldVolleyballAthletics & Sports InformationStaff DirectoryRecruiting CentralAthletics NewsTicket InformationMonarchs Hall of FameShop Monarch AthleticsYouth Summer CampsAlumni & FriendsFor AlumniAlumni AffairsAlumni BenefitsAlumni EventsHomecomingAlumni AwardsAlumni TravelGiving to MUDonate Now OnlineInstitutional AdvancementWays to GiveLoyalty CampaignAnnual FundAlumni GivingAlumni & Friends ResourcesAlumni & Advancement StaffParent ProgramsMU Today MagazineSubmit Class NotesRequest a TranscriptMU License PlatesThe MU JourneyCommunity EngagementAbout the CenterReligious LifeCommunity PartnersCommunity Engagement FellowsGlobal EducationAbout the CenterGlobal FellowsGlobal Education CertificateStudy AbroadLeadership DevelopmentAbout the Lura S. Tally CenterLeadership FellowsShelton Leadership CampSpeaker SeriesResearch & CreativityAbout the CenterURC FellowsMonarch ReviewPresenting Your ResearchSocial MediaFacebookTwitterInstagramPinterestSnapchatLinkedInFlickrYouTubeMethodist University > About Methodist University > Privacy Policy Methodist University is firmly committed to protecting your privacy.  This Privacy Policy applies to data collection and usage of our website. Methodist University respects your privacy and uses collected data in accordance with applicable laws.The University collects personally identifiable information (PII) that you submit, or permit us to obtain from third parties, for purposes relevant to University operations in pursuit of its mission. Examples of such information include email address, name, address, information needed for student admission (including financial aid information), employment, gifts/fundraising, and institutional research.  We also collect data in the form of cookies, forms, websites logs and email tracking.  We do not sell personally identifiable information to third parties.  We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of third-party websites.Please be aware that PII you directly disclose through blogs/comments may be collected and used by others.Data CollectionCookiesCookies are messages passed from a website to and stored in an individual user’s web browser.  Each time an individual visits the same website, the information is passed back to the server.  The primary purpose of this is convenience by telling the web server you have returned to a particular page. This allows Methodist University to identify repeat visitors to the website.  The University and third parties acting on our behalf may store and read information from a cookie that the University has placed in an individual web browser.You have the ability to accept or decline cookies.  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you wish.Logs and Email TrackingThe University generally logs activity and usage of our website.  Such logging includes, but is not limited to IP addresses, session information (from cookies), pages visited on the University website, browser information, date and time, length of visit, email addressFormsIn the normal course of business such as admissions, donations, etc. we may require an individual to enter various information into forms on a website.  The data may include PII.Data UsageMethodist University will not sell personally identifiable information collected on its website to third parties.  The University uses all collected data in accordance with applicable laws including but not limited to HIPAA and FERPA.  The University may use information collected from cookies to track and pass session data.  Data collected from forms will be used to respond an inquiry or process the request.  Finally, the University may use logs to compile data regarding our website.SecurityMethodist University secures personal information from unauthorized use, access and disclosure in a controlled, secure environment.  Access to this information is provided on the principle of least privileges.  The transmission of personal information is protected through the use of encryption. This policy is subject to review, modification, amendment and/or termination at any time and at the sole and absolute discretion of the University.  The University encourages you to periodically review this statement.By promulgation and/or implementation of this policy, the University does not accept any responsibility or liability for the actions (of commission and/or omission) of third parties or for use by the public of any publicly accessible website or other electronic portal. To that end, the University disclaims any and all such liability and responsibility, express or implied, to the fullest extent allowable under all applicable laws and regulations. Be advised that all such use is at the users own risk.
Share
Tweet
Messenger
Pinterest
Share
reddit
Email
Search for:
About MUOur Vision & MissionUniversity ProfileAbout Our Relationship to the United Methodist ChurchA Brief History of Methodist UniversityAdministrative CabinetThe MU JourneyRecent NewsFor Campus VisitorsCampus DirectoryCampus MapsDriving DirectionsArea HotelsArts & Lecture SeriesMcCune GalleryUpcoming EventsPrivacy PolicyAdministrative OfficesAll Campus OfficesPresident & TrusteesBookstoreBook Our VenuesComputer ServicesController’s OfficeHousekeeping & MaintenanceHuman ResourcesInstitutional Research & EffectivenessMail CenterOffice of Student AccountsUniversity RelationsWelcome to MU!Join Us at MU!MU on Social Media      ContactPhone: (910) 630-7000 Toll-Free: (800) 488-7110Main MenuAbout Methodist UniversityAcademicsAdmissionsFinancial AidStudent AffairsAthleticsAlumni & FriendsThe MU JourneyQuick LinksmyMU PortalCanvasGroupWise E-MailGive to MUForward Together: COVID-19 ResourcesDavis Memorial LibraryBookstoreOnline ProgramsRequest a TranscriptNon-Discrimination StatementMethodist University does not discriminate on the basis of age, race, gender, national or ethnic origin, religion, sexual orientation, or disabilities in its programs and activities.
